ASHUTHOSH M. R.

M. Tech (by Research) Student in Electronics and Communication Engineering

ashuthosh.de

ashuthosh-mr

in ashuthosh-mr

@ ashuthoshmr@pes.edu



WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant CHIPS, PES University Research Foundation

September 2020 - Ongoing

Bengaluru, IN

- Worked on projects involving accelerating matrix multiplication on FP-GAs, accelerating graph algorithms using RISC-V based FPGA overlays.
- Assisted in RISC-V on FPGA lab sessions for undergraduate students.

Research Assistant - Intern CAcHe Lab, Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham

☐ January 2020 - May 2020

Remote

- This research was conducted as part of the ECHO(Error Correcting Codes in High performance and parallel architectures) Indo-Portugal project.
- Our work focused on creating robust ${\sf GF}(2^m)$ NB-LDPC decoder designs on FPGA, comparing performance metrics against GPUs

PUBLICATIONS

Patent

 M. Purnaprajna, A. M. Ravikumar, and S. Krishna, "Run-time reconfigurable accelerator for matrix multiplication," in US Patent Application US20230029761A1, 2021.

Journal Articles

• S. Subramaniyan, O. Ferraz, M. R. Ashuthosh, et al., "Enabling high-level design strategies for high-throughput and low-power NB-LDPC decoders," *IEEE Design Test Journal*, vol. 40, 2022.

Conference Proceedings

- M. R. Ashuthosh, S. Krishna, V. Sudarshan, S. Subramaniyan, and M. Purnaprajna, "MAPPARAT: A resource constrained fpgabased accelerator for sparse-dense matrix multiplication," in 35th International Conference on VLSI Design and 21st International Conference on Embedded Systems (VLSID) (Best Paper Award), Bengaluru, India, 2022.
- S. Subramaniyan, O. Ferraz, M. R. Ashuthosh, et al., "Pushing the limits of energy efficiency for non-binary LDPC decoders on GPUs and FPGAs," in *IEEE Workshop on Signal Processing Systems* (SiPS), Coimbra, Portugal, 2020.

Poster

M. R. Ashuthosh, A. Vinay, K. K. Nagar, and M. Purnaprajna, "Accelerating BFS algorithm on a RISC-V based many-core cluster," in 30th IEEE International Conference on High Performance Computing, Data, Analytics, Student Research Symposium, Goa, India, 2023.

SUMMARY

I am a second-year M. Tech student at Centre for Heterogeneous and Intelligent Processing Systems advised by Prof. Madhura Purnaprajna. My research interests include designing digital systems on FPGAs, parallel computer architecture and graph algorithms.

EDUCATION

M. Tech (by Research) **PES University**

May 2022 - Ongoing

- Advised by Prof. Madhura Purnaprajna
- Working on accelerating graph algorithms on custom architectures.

B.E. in Electronics and Communication Engineering

PESIT - Bangalore South Campus

🗖 August 2016 - July 2020

Graduated with 7.96/10 CGPA

SKILLS

Verilog HDL & FPGAs RISC-V OpenMP

ETEX Python Verilator Ubuntu

NPTEL CERTIFICATIONS

- Computer Architecture: 80% (Topper's list)
- Introduction to Parallel Programming with OpenMP and MPI: 75% (Topper's list)
- VLSI Design Flow: RTL to GDS: 80%
- C-based VLSI Design: 75%

LEISURE

Astro-Photography

Watching F1, football

LANGUAGES

Kannada English Hindi Tulu Malayalam German

